THE GREAT BRITISH CODING RELAY
An ambulance arrives.
A patient episode begins.
The hi-vis pigeon has already
opened an incident ticket.
DOCTORS TREAT. THEN DOCUMENT.
Notes. Scans. Discharge summaries.
More notes.
And one mysterious sentence
copied forward since Tuesday.
ENTER: CLINICAL CODING
Across NHS trusts, coding teams
can run to 30+ specialists.
They read the whole episode.
Years to master. Labour-intensive.
Ripe for careful automation.
CLINICAL CHAOS → ICD-10 + OPCS-4
The codes drive reimbursement,
epidemiology and planning.
No codes, no money. Finance starts
breathing into a paper bag.
AI COULD HELP. TINY PROBLEM: DATA.
Patient records are sensitive.
You cannot simply download a ward.
USA: MIMIC-IV — reusable, US-specific.
UK: OPCS-4, governance, tea.
SO WE BUILT THE TEST TRACK
UK-specific synthetic training episodes
+ a benchmark for coding AI products.
Catch hallucinations before they invoice anyone.
THE MVP: EPICODE-Bench
All the coding drama. None of the data breach.